LAC0014
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Trade Unions - Railroads Collection
1936-1975
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
LAC0014
1.75 Linear Feet
- Subject Files, 1936-1975; Series 1; 1 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains material related to railroad trade unions, companies, and industry associations dating from 1936-1975. Included are pamphlets, news clippings, company and trade union histories, reports, correspondence, insurance and retirement information, and other miscellaneous items related to history and operation of the railroad industry.
  - The American Short Line Railroad Association, 1969; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Association of American Railroads, 1954-1967; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brotherhood Railway Carmen of America, 1954; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1975; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Railroads, 1936-1951; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Group Insurance Policy Information [1/2], 1955-1968; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Group Insurance Policy Information [2/2], 1955-1966; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - News Clippings, 1957-1972; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlets, 1939-1972; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Railroad Accidents, 1946-1957; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Railroad Company Annual Reports, 1967-1972; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Railroad Histories [1/2], 1937-1956; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Railroad Histories [2/2], 1962-1970; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Railway Mileage Development, 1939; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Railway Progress Insitutue, 1964-1965; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reports [1/2], 1958-1962; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reports [2/2], 1966-1970; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Retirement, 1951-1965; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Trade Union Histories, 1951-1964; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Train Schedules, 1970; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Transportation Association of America, undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - United Transportation Union, 1971; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Union Pacific Railroad, 1972; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Railway Labor Executives' Association, 1937-1965; Series 2; 0.75 Linear Feet
  This series contains material from the Railway Labor Executives' Association, a federation of railroad labor unions involved in advocacy, policy lobbying. The materials date from 1936-1975. Included are correspondence, news releases, railway labor fact sheets, weekly legislative reports, and miscellaneous other items produced by the operation of the Association.
  - Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Dispute, 1937 June; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Carriers Joint Conference Committee Proceedings, 1938; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum to the Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, House of Representatives, 1940; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - News Releases, 1959-1960; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - News Releases, 1961; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - News Releases, 1962; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - News Releases, 1963 January - May; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - News Releases, 1963 May - November; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - News Releases, 1964; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - News Releases, 1965; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Railway Labor Fact Sheets, 1959-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Weekly Legislative Reports, 1965; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)